Finding Aid for the Christine Sadler Coe Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Writings – Books – unpublished –America’s First Princess: Nelly Parke Custis Lewis
  - Research material – correspondence re: photographs and letters (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Research material – Last will – Eleanor Parke Lewis (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Research material – Final illness and obituary – Eleanor Parke Lewis (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Research material – draft of article “ Goose Grease and Deer Suet are Good when Heels are Sore” (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Research material – Last will – Lorenzo Lewis (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Research material – Last will – Lawrence Lewis, March 1839 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Research material – Letters of Lawrence Lewis re: George Washington Estate (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Research material – Last will – David Stuart, 1814 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Draft of article “Whatever Happened to Nelly Custis?” (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Research material – letters E.G.W. Butler/Andrew Jackson (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Research material – letters E. G. W. Butler/Andrew Jackson (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Research material – letters E.G.W. Butler/Andrew Jackson (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Research material – letters E.G.W. Butler/Andrew Jackson (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Research material – letters E.G.W. Butler/Andrew Jackson (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Research material – letters E.G.W. Butler (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Research material – letters E.G.W. Butler (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Research material – letters E.G.W. Butler (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Research material – letters E.G.W. Butler (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Research material – letters E.G.W. Butler (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Research material – letters E.G.W. Butler (Box 30, Folder 22)
- Writings – Books – unpublished –America’s First Princess: Nelly Parke Custis Lewis
  - Research material – Woodlawn Plantation (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Research material – Woodlawn Plantation (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Research material – Woodlawn Plantation and other historic properties (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Research material – Woodlawn Plantation; Custis - Lee Mansion; Pope - Leighy House (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Research material – letters written when Pearl retired at Woodlawn (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Research material – Hope Park (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Research material – “Old Arlington” the story of the Lee Mansion National Monument, U.S. Department of the Interior by Murray H. Nelligan (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Research material - portraits (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Research material- Washington – Custis - Lee family portraits catalogue (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Research material – articles (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Research material – newspaper articles (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Research material – family letters (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Research material – family (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Research material – family (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Research material (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Research material (Box 31, Folder 16)
- Writings – Books – unpublished –America’s First Princess: Nelly Parke Custis Lewis
  - Research material (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Research material (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Research material (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Research material (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Research material (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Writings – Research Material related to other projects
  - American Ideals versus the New Deal by Herbert Hoover, nine addresses by Hoover, 1935 – 36 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - “Three Years of Dr. Roosevelt” by H.L. Mencken, 1936; “If the New Dealers Win” by Frank R. Kent (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - “Our Contribution” address by Bainbridge Colby, January 27, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - “The White House: a Bibliographical List, Supplement, 1952 – 1960” The Library of Congress (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - The Presidents of he United States, 1789 – 1962: A Selected List of Reference (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Gilbert Stuart: Portraitist of the Young Republic, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Historic Preservation – October – December 1972 and April – June, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - American History Illustrated, May 1974; July 1978 (Box 32, Folder 13)
- Writings by others – Coe, Richard L.
  - Reviews – 1940’s – 1950’s (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Reviews – 1960’s (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Reviews – 1970’s (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Reviews – undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Reviews – Richard II – typescript, August 1974 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Reviews and articles relating to President Eisenhower, 1950’s – 1960’s (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Review and letter – J.F. Kennedy (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Review – Jimmy Carter’s Inauguration, January 1977 (Box 33, Folder 8)
- Writings by others
  - Hussein, Aziza “The Role of Women in Social Reform in Egypt” reprint from The Middle East Journal, vol. 7, no. 4, Autumn 1953 (Box 33, Folder 9)
- Subject Files – People and topics
  - Acheson, Dean (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - American Writers – Calendar (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Amram, David (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Astor, Nancy (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Baker, Howard (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Baker, Russell (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Boggs, Hale and Lindy (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Book dustjackets (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Boorstein, Daniel (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Bradley, General Omar N. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Calendars, 1700-2083 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Canada (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Carpenter, Liz (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Channing, Carol (Mrs. Charles Lowe) (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Charles II – biography by Antonia Fraser (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Cheney, Brainard (Lon) and Frances Neel (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Churchill, Winston (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Columbus, Christopher (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Dickerson, Nancy (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Douglas, Mary Stahlman (journalist) (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Douglas, Justice William O. (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Durant, Will (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Eisenhower Family (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Falkner, Maud (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Gordon, Caroline (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Great Britain’s Royal Family – the Tudors – Henry VIII and Elizabeth I (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Great Britain’s Royal Family – Queen Victoria and Prince Albert (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Great Britain’s Royal Family – The Windsors (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Great Britain’s Royal Family – The Windsors- Queen Elizabeth II (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - Great Britain’s Royal Family – The Windsors – Charles and Diana (Box 34, Folder 31)
- Subject Files – People and topics
  - Great Britain’s Royal Family – The Windsors – Charles and Diana (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Great Britain’s Royal Family – The Windsors – Charles and Diana (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Great Britain’s Royal Family – The Windsors – Charles and Diana (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain’s Royal Family – The Windsors – Duke and Duchess of Windsor (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Greece (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - The Hermitage (Russia) (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Heroes (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Hersey, John (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Humphrey, Hubert (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - James, Henry (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Journalists (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Joyce, James (Ulysses) (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Kefauver, Estes (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Kennedy Family – Caroline Kennedy (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Kennedy Family – Edward Kennedy (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Kennedy Family – Mrs. Edward Kennedy (Joan) (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Kennedy Family – Joseph P. Kennedy (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Kennedy Family – Mrs. Joseph P. Kennedy (Rose) (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Kennedy Family – Robert F. Kennedy (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Lindbergh, Charles and Anne Morrow (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Luce, Clare Boothe (Box 35, Folder 21)
- Subject Files – People and topics
  - Map of the World (Hammond) (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Maugham, W. Somerset (novelist) (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Michener, James (novelist) (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Moore, Dr. Merrill ( Fugitive poet) (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Morrison, Samuel Eliot (historian) (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - National Gallery of Art, Washington, D.C.- 25th Anniversary Exhibit (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - New Hampshire – Dartmouth College (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - The New Yorker – 50 years (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - The New Yorker – articles (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Harnsworth, Alfred Lord Northcliffe (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Orwell, George (pen name of Eric Arthur Blair, writer) (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Parkhurst, Sylvia (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Pearl Harbor (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Perelman, S. J. (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Perkins, Frances (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Poems “Cyrano de Bergerac” “Faust” “Oedipus Rex” “The Second” “Trilby” (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Presidents of the United States (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Presidents of the U.S. and their children (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Reagan, President Ronald (1981 – 1989) (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Robinson, Francis (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Rukeyser, Louis (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Secret Service (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Shaw, George Bernard (playwright) (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Shirer, William (journalist) (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - Silver, James (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Silver, James and Maud Falkner, University of Mississippi 1956 (1) (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - Silver, James and Maud Falkner, University of Mississippi 1956 (2) (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - Silver, James and Maud Falkner, University of Mississippi 1956 (3) (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - Silver, James and Maud Falkner, University of Mississippi 1956 (4) (Box 36, Folder 29)
- Subject Files – People and topics
  - Smith, Senator Margaret Chase (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Stowe, Harriet Beecher (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Tennessee – President James K. Polk (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Tennessee (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Tennessee (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Tennessee (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Tennessee (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Tennessee (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Tennessee – research notes (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Tennessee – Annals of Tennessee – Research notes (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Tennessee – Research notes and maps (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Tuchman, Barbara (historian) (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Twain, Mark (Samuel Clemens) (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - United States Civil War (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - United States Government Publications (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Uzbekistan (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Waugh, Evelyn (novelist) (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Wharton, Edith (writer) (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - White, Theodore H. (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Wodehouse, P.G. (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Ziegler, Ron (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Miscellany – Book reviews (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Miscellany – Books of interest – reviews (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Miscellany – Scrapbooks, 1935-1937 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Miscellany Photographs – Official (Box 37, Folder 25)
- Portraits and Personal Christine Sadler Coe
  - Washington Post, 1946-1961 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Color portrait by Harris & Ewing, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Individual portraits by McMillan (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - “Ingredients for Mamie’s Fudge” – Women’s National Press Club Cookbook (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Personal (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Personal – vacation – undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Personal – 1970’s? (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Personal – at home in Washington, D.C. – undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - CSC and Richard Coe – September 4, 1957 – departing on board “Queen Mary” for the Washington Post (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - CSC and Richard Coe (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - People – Richard L. Coe (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - People – Richard L. Coe (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - People – Jones, Alexander F., Managing editor of the Post; Folliard, Edward T., White House Correspondent for the WP with CSC (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - People – Harris, Patricia Roberts (U.S. Ambassador to Luxenbourg; Charlotte Moton Hubbard(Deputy Assistant Secretary of State) (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - People – Therese Bonny; Ruth Van Demon (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - People – Hull, Cordell with Frances Perkins and CSC, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - People – Johnson, Mrs. Lyndon B. (Lady Bird) with Christine and Richard Coe in Texas; CSC at White House Luncheon (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - People – Johnson, Lynda Bird, June 11, 1965 with CSC (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - People – Riley, Dr. Susan B. (Peabody College faculty) (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - People – Roosevelt, Eleanor and Otis L. Wiese at reception, c. late 1940’s with CSC (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - People – Silver, Gail, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - People – Smith, Senator Margaret Chase; Frances P. Bolton (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - People – Taylor, W. H. with CSC (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - People – Women Ambassadors, State Department: Hernandez, Aileen; Larsen, Carol C.; Louchheim, Katie; others not identified (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - People – A – L: Mildred C. Ahlgren; Reva Buck Bison (sp?); Burdett, Mrs. Harold; Butler, Sally; Capper, Arthur; Joe L. Evins family; Gunderson, Bob; Hendrick, Jim and Elinor; Haston, Evelyn; James, Jinny (Jamie); Listebarger, Jean with CSC (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - People – M – Z: Snedegar, Mrs. Nunally; Moyer, Blanche; Monroe, Harriet; O’Malley, Patricia; Rogers, Congresswoman Edith Nourse; Philip, Henry and Earl James; Seaburg, G. Z.; Talbot, Kate (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - People and Events; - CSC with unidentified (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - People and Events – CSC with unidentified c. 1960’s? (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - People – Family – Johnson, Kay and John with children (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - People – Family – Kimberlee, Bevan, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - People – Family – Sadler? (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - People – Family – Sadler/ Lundy (Box 38, Folder 32)
  - People – Family – Sadler/ Lundy (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - People – Family – Sadler/ Lundy (Box 38, Folder 34)
  - People – Family – Lundy (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - People – Family – with some identification (Box 38, Folder 36)
  - People – Family – with some identification (Box 38, Folder 37)
  - People – Family – unidentified, 1963 (Box 38, Folder 38)
  - People – Family –unidentified (Box 38, Folder 39)
- Photographs – People and Places
  - People – Family – unidentified (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - People – Family – unidentified (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - People – Family – unidentified (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - People – Family –unidentified (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - People – Family – unidentified (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - People – unidentified (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - People – unidentified (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Places – Rugby, Tennessee – Hughes House; Hughes Public Library (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Places – House and garden in Washington, D.C., 1966 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Places – House and Garden in Washington, D.C., Dumbarton Oaks, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Places – Garden in Washington, D.C. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Places – Lake Louise; Glacier Bay, June 1979 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Places – Kennedy’s Castle (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Places – New Castle, Delaware –historic buildings (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Places – Middleburg, Virginia; Fairfax Court House, VA (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Places – unidentified (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Artwork by CSC (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Slides (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Negatives (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Negatives (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Negatives (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Negatives (Box 39, Folder 22)
- Photographs – Events – Professional
  - Republican National Convention in Philadelphia, 1940, CSC with Washington Post Staff (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - World War II Wave Link School, 1942-1943 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Colonel Oveta Culp Hobby, Director of Women’s Army Corps receives picture from McCall’s, October 13, 1944; Oveta Hobby and Jean Knox, October 12, 1942 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - CSC receiving the “Cora Rigby” bowl from Esther Tufty, c. 1950’s (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Woman’s National Democratic Club – c. 1950’s (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Album of Visit of U.S. Newspapermen to Mexico, March 1952 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Visit to Mexico, D.M. Nacional, March 1952 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Visit to Mexico, D.M. Nacional, March 1952 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Visit to Mexico, D.M. Nacional, March 1952 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Visit to Mexico, D.M. Nacional, March 1952 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Visit to Mexico, D.M. Nacional, March 1952 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - National Press Club, CSC with unidentified, undated (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - CSC at Nashville Airport with unidentified, March 1956; at Nashville luncheon (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - McCall’s Award Dinner in St. Louis with Sophie Altman, April 27, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - “Red Apple” Citations, Cosmos Club, Washington, D.C. CSC with Dean Edward W. Barrett; Howard P. Jones; Hollington Tong; Mrs. Barrett, November 20, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Members of the Defense Advisory Committee on Women, 1956 – 1958 (all identified) (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Press Conference – McCall’s Conference on Better Living, October 10, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - American Women in Radio and Television, April 25, 1958: CSC; Vera Mellenshick; Kathryn Bell; June I. Rainey (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - White House Presentation, September 30, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Teacher of the Year reception, 1958: Dr. and Mrs. Lawrence Derthick and Frank Hogan (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - CSC with her book America’s First Ladies, 1963 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Trip to Federal Republic of Germany, July 1964 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Wives Seminar State Department Foreign Service, April 1967 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Education trip with First Lady Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson, April 1967 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - CSC book signing Children in the White House, 1967 with Lynda Bird Johnson (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Trip with Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson – CSC; Isabelle Shelton, Malvina Stephenson, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - ANUC Awards Dinner, May 19, 1968: CSC; unidentified at Shoreham Hotel (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - American Council for the Arts, November 1977 –Christine Sadler Coe and Richard Coe with Joan Mondale (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - McCall’s goodbye party, undated (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Tennessee Float-Parade, Washington, D.C. undated (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - CSC at the White House with unidentified, undated (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - CSC with Else Strom; Can Madeline; Harnaday, Mary; Tree, Anne Cottrell; McDowell, Lee; Gaylor, Edith, undated (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - CSC address to Florida Federation of Women’s Clubs, Miami Beach, undated (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - Undated, unidentified (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - Undated, unidentified (Box 40, Folder 35)
  - Undated, unidentified (Box 40, Folder 36)
- Photographs – Events – Professional and Personal
  - Undated, unidentified (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - unidentified, 1959-1965 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Christmas, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Christmas, 1964 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Christmas, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Christmas, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Christmas – undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Christmas – undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Visit to Tennessee State Park, c. 1962 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Vacation at a beach, August 1967 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Vacation to Williamsburg, Virginia, 1967 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Vacation at a beach, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Vacation at a beach, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - August 1973 – “Tallulah: a Memory” Central City Opera House, Colorado; portrait of Tallulah by Augustus John (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Archaeology dig – undated (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Archaeology dig – undated (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Visit to Shiloh with James Silver and Richard Coe, undated (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook photographs, 1946-1947 (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Scrapbook photographs – 1946 -1947 – Richard L. Coe in “Aida” a performance by Philadelphia’s La Scala Opera in Washington, D.C. (Box 41, Folder 19)
- Photographs - First Ladies- used for America’s First Ladies
  - Mrs. George Washington (Martha Custis) (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Mrs. Daniel Parke Custis (Martha Dandridge) (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Mrs. John Adams (Abigail Smith) (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Mrs. Thomas Jefferson (Martha Skelton) (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Martha Jefferson Randolph (Mrs. Thomas Mann Randolph) daughter and hostess of Thomas Jefferson (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - Mrs. James Madison (Dolley) (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Mrs. James Monroe (Elizabeth Kortright) (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Mrs. John Quincy Adams (Louisa Catherine Johnson) (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - Mrs. Andrew Jackson ( Rachel) (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Mrs. Andrew Jackson Donelson (Emily) hostess for Andrew Jackson (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - Mrs. Martin Van Buren (died before he became President) (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - Jane Irwin Findlay – hostess for President William Henry Harrison (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - Mrs. John Tyler (Latitia) first wife (Box 41, Folder 32)
  - Mrs. John Tyler (Julia Gardiner) (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - Mrs. James K. Polk (Sarah Childress) (Box 41, Folder 34)
  - Betty Taylor Bliss – hostess for her father President Zachary Taylor Ann Mackall Taylor –daughter of President Zachary Taylor (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - Mrs. Millard Fillmore (Abigail Powers) (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Mrs. Franklin Pierce (with her son Bennie) (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - Harriet Lane Johnston (niece of President James Buchanan and his White House hostess) (Box 41, Folder 38)
  - Mrs. Abraham Lincoln (Mary Todd) (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - Martha Johnson Patterson (Mrs. David Patterson) daughter of Andrew Johnson and hostess during his term of office (Box 41, Folder 40)
  - Mrs. Ulysses S. Grant (Julia) (Box 41, Folder 41)
  - Mrs. Rutherford B. Hayes (Lucy Webb) (Box 41, Folder 42)
  - Mrs. James Garfield (Lucretia Rudolph) (Box 41, Folder 43)
  - Mary Arthur McElroy ( sister and hostess for Chester A. Arthur) (Box 41, Folder 44)
- Photographs – used for America’s First Ladies
  - Mrs. Chester Arthur (Ellen Lewis Herndon) (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Rose Elizabeth Cleveland ( hostess for her brother Grover Cleveland) (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Mrs. Grover Cleveland (Frances Folsom) (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Mrs. Benjamin Harrison (Caroline Lavinia) (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Mrs. Benjamin Harrison ( Anna Symmes) (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Mrs. William McKinley (Ida Saxton) (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Mrs. Theodore Roosevelt (Edith Carow) (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Mrs. William Howard Taft (Helen) (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Mrs. Woodrow Wilson (Ellen Axson – first wife) (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - President Woodrow Wilson and Mrs. Galt (2nd Mrs. Wilson) (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - President and Mrs. Warren G. Harding (Florence Kling) (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Mrs. Calvin Coolidge (Grace); Ellen Wayles Randolph Coolidge (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Mrs. Herbert Hoover ( Lou Henry) (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Mrs. Franklin D. Roosevelt ( Eleanor) (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Mrs. Harry Truman (Bess Wallace) (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Mrs. Dwight D. Eisenhower (Mamie Geneva Doud) (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Mrs. John F. Kennedy (Jacqueline Bouvier) (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson ( Claudia Alta Taylor known as Lady Bird); Zephyr Wright (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Unidentified first ladies (Box 42, Folder 19)
- Photographs – Presidential Families – used for America’s First Ladies and Children in the White House
  - George Washington (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - John Adams (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Thomas Jefferson (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - James Madison (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - James Monroe (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - John Quincy Adams (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Andrew Jackson (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Martin Van Buren (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - William Henry Harrison (no photos) (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - John Tyler (no photos) (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - James K. Polk (no photos) (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Zachary Taylor (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Millard Fillmore (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Franklin Pierce (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - James Buchanan (no photos) (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Abraham Lincoln (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Andrew Johnson (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Ulysses S. Grant (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Rutherford B. Hayes (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - James A. Garfield (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Chester A. Arthur (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Grover Cleveland (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Benjamin Harrison (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - William McKinley (no photos) (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Theodore Roosevelt (Box 43, Folder 25)